<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
<character><version>37</version><uid>1013</uid><name>Haey</name><race><name>Tiefling</name><feat><name>Vision dans le noir (18m)</name><text>Grâce à votre héritage infernal, vous avez une vision supérieure dans le noir et les conditions de faible éclairage. Vous pouvez voir à 18 mètres dans une lumière faible comme vous verriez avec une lumière vive, et dans le noir comme vous verriez avec une lumière faible. Dans le noir, vous ne discernez pas les couleurs, uniquement des nuances de gris.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Résistance infernale</name><text>Vous avez la résistance aux dégâts de feu.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Ascendance infernale</name><text>Vous connaissez le sort mineur thaumaturgie. Quand vous atteignez le niveau 3, vous pouvez lancer le sort représailles infernales comme un sort de niveau 2 une fois avec ce trait et regagnez cette capacité lorsque vous terminez un repos long. Quand vous atteignez le niveau 5, vous pouvez lancer le sort ténèbres une fois avec ce trait et regagnez cette capacité lorsque vous terminez un repos long. Le Charisme est votre caractéristique d&#39;incantation pour ces sorts.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Langues (Commun, Infernal)</name><text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Infernal.
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 43</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><mod><category>1</category><type>3</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><category>1</category><type>5</type><value>2</value></mod><spellAbility>5</spellAbility><spell><name>Thaumaturgy</name><school>8</school><time>1 action</time><range>30 feet</range><v>1</v><duration>Up to 1 minute</duration><text>You manifest a minor wonder, a sign of supernatural power, within range. You create one of the following magical effects within range:
	 • Your voice booms up to three times as loud as normal for 1 minute. 
	• You cause flames to flicker, brighten, dim, or change color for 1 minute. 
	• You cause harmless tremors in the ground for 1 minute. 
	• You create an instantaneous sound that originates from a point of your choice within range, such as a rumble of thunder, the cry of a raven, or ominous whispers. 
	• You instantaneously cause an unlocked door or window to fly open or slam shut. 
	• You alter the appearance of your eyes for 1 minute. 
	If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its 1-minute effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 282</text><sclass>Cleric</sclass></spell><spell><name>Hellish Rebuke</name><school>5</school><level>1</level><time>1 reaction</time><range>60 feet</range><v>1</v><s>1</s><duration>Instantaneous</duration><text>You point your finger, and the creature that damaged you is momentarily surrounded by hellish flames. The creature must make a Dexterity saving throw. It takes 2d10 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. 
	
At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 1st.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 250</text><roll>2d10</roll><sclass>Warlock</sclass></spell></race><class><id>1011</id><name>Rogue</name><level>4</level><hd>2</hd><hdCurrent>4</hdCurrent><wealth>4d4x10</wealth><proficiency>108</proficiency><proficiency>111</proficiency><proficiency>103</proficiency><proficiency>1</proficiency><proficiency>3</proficiency><proficiency>107</proficiency><numClassSkills>4</numClassSkills><armor>armures légères</armor><weapons>armes courantes, arbalète de poing, épée courte, épée longue, rapière</weapons><tools>outils de voleur, kit de deguisement, kit de poison</tools><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><feat><name>Expertise</name><text>Au niveau 1, choisissez deux des compétences que vous maîtrisez, ou l&#39;une d&#39;elles et votre maîtrise des outils de voleur. Votre bonus de maîtrise est doublé pour tout jet de caractéristique que vous réalisez et qui utilise l&#39;une des compétences choisies.

Au niveau 6, vous pouvez choisir deux maîtrises supplémentaires (compétences ou outils de voleur) et obtenir le même avantage.

	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text><expanded>0</expanded><mod><category>4</category><type>16</type></mod><mod><category>4</category><type>11</type></mod></feat><feat><name>Attaque sournoise</name><text>À partir du niveau 1, vous savez comment trouver et exploiter subtilement la distraction d&#39;un ennemi. Une fois par tour, vous pouvez infliger 1d6 points de dégâts supplémentaires à une créature que vous réussissez à toucher si vous avez l&#39;avantage au jet d&#39;attaque. L&#39;attaque doit utiliser une arme de finesse ou une arme à distance. Vous n&#39;avez pas besoin d&#39;avoir l&#39;avantage au jet d&#39;attaque si un autre ennemi de la cible est à 1,50 mètre ou moins de celle-ci, que cet ennemi n&#39;est pas incapable d&#39;agir, et que vous n&#39;avez pas un désavantage au jet d&#39;attaque. Le nombre de dégâts supplémentaires augmente à mesure que vous gagnez des niveaux dans cette classe, comme indiqué dans la colonne Attaque sournoise de la table ci-dessous:

Niv     #d6
1        1d6
2        1d6
3        2d6
4        2d6
5        3d6
6        3d6
7        4d6
8        4d6
9        5d6
...

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat><feat><name>Jargon des voleurs</name><text>Au cours de votre formation de roublard, vous avez appris le jargon des voleurs, un mélange secret de dialecte, de jargon et de codes, qui vous permet de cacher des messages dans une conversation apparemment normale. Seule une autre créature qui connaît le jargon des voleurs comprend ces messages. Il faut quatre fois plus de temps pour transmettre un tel message qu&#39;il ne le faudrait pour transmettre la même idée clairement.

En outre, vous comprenez un ensemble de signes et de symboles secrets utilisés pour transmettre des messages courts et simples, comme pour indiquer qu&#39;une zone est dangereuse ou qu&#39;elle fait partie du territoire d&#39;une guilde des voleurs, qu&#39;un butin est à proximité, ou que les gens d&#39;une région sont des proies faciles ou qu&#39;ils fourniront une maison sûre pour des voleurs en fuite.

	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Ruse</name><text>À partir du niveau 2, votre vivacité d&#39;esprit et votre agilité vous permettent de vous déplacer et d&#39;agir rapidement. Vous pouvez effectuer une action bonus à chacun de vos tours en combat. Cette action ne peut être utilisée que pour Se désengager, Se cacher ou Foncer.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat><feat><name>Archétype de roublard: Assassin</name><text>Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Maîtrises supplémentaires</name><text>Lorsque vous choisissez cet archétype au niveau 3, vous gagnez la maîtrise du kit de déguisement et du kit d&#39;empoisonneur.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Assassinat</name><text>À partir du niveau 3, vous êtes au summum de votre art lorsque vous prenez votre adversaire au dépourvu. Vous avez l&#39;avantage à vos jets d&#39;attaque contre toute créature qui n&#39;a pas encore joué son tour durant le combat. En outre, si vous attaquez et touchez une créature surprise, cette attaque est considérée comme un coup critique.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><mod><name>Ability Score Improvement (4th Level)</name><category>1</category><type>1</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><name>Ability Score Improvement (4th Level)</name><category>1</category><type>5</type><value>1</value></mod><autolevel><slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Starting Rogue</name><text>As a 1st-level Rogue, you begin play with 8+your Constitution modifier hit points.
 
You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
• Armor: light armor
• Weapons: simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords
• Tools: thieves&#39; tools
• Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth
 
You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.
• (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword
• (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword
• (a) a burglar&#39;s pack, (b) a dungeoneer&#39;s pack, or (c) an explorer&#39;s pack
• Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves&#39; tools 
 
Alternatively, you may start with 4d4x10 gp and choose your own equipment.
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 94</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Multiclass Rogue</name><text>To multiclass as a Rogue, you must meet the following prerequisites:
• Dexterity 13
 
You gain the following proficiencies:
• light armor, thieves&#39; tools; choose one skill from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance. Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 163</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Expertise</name><text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves’ tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.
	At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with thieves’ tools) to gain this benefit.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat><feat><name>Sneak Attack</name><text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe’s distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.
	You don’t need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn’t incapacitated, and you don’t have disadvantage on the attack roll.
	The amount of the extra damage increases by 1d6 every odd level you gain in this class, to a maximum of 10d6 at 19th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat><feat><name>Thieves&#39; Cant</name><text>During your rogue training you learned thieves’ cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves’ cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.
	In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves’ guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>2</level><slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Cunning Action</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, your quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>3</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Roguish Archetype</name><text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you emulate in the exercise of your rogue abilities: Thief, Assassin, or Arcane Trickster, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your archetype choice grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat><feat><name>Roguish Archetype: Arcane Trickster</name><text>Some rogues enhance their fine-honed skills of stealth and agility with magic, learning tricks of enchantment and illusion. These rogues include pickpockets and burglars, but also pranksters, mischief-makers, and a significant number of adventurers.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Spellcasting (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>When you reach 3rd level, you gain the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list. 
	 
Cantrips: You learn three cantrips: mage hand and two other cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn another wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level. 
	 
Spell Slots: The Arcane Trickster Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	For example. if you know the 1st-level spell charm person and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast charm person using either slot. 
	 
Spells Known of 1st-Level and Higher: You know three 1st-level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the enchantment and illusion spells on the wizard spell list. 
	You learn one additional spell at 4th, 7th, 8th, 10th, 11th, 13th, 14th, 16th, 19th, and 20th level. Each of these spells must be an enchantment or illusion spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this c1ass. you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level. 
	The spells you learn at 8th. 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic. 
	Whenever you gain a level in this c1ass, you can replace one of the wizard spells you know with another spell of your choice from the wizard spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be an enchantment or illusion spell, unless you’re replacing the spell you gained at 8th, 14th, or 20th level. 
	 
Spellcasting Ability: Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through dedicated study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. 
	 
Spell save DC = 8+your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier 
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 98</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Mage Hand Legerdemain (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, when you cast mage hand, you can make the spectral hand invisible, and you can perform the following additional tasks with it.
	 
• You can stow one object the hand is holding in a container worn or carried by another creature.
	 
• You can retrieve an object in a container worn or carried by another creature.
	 
• You can use thieves’ tools to pick locks and disarm traps at range.
	 
	You can perform one of these tasks without being noticed by a creature if you succeed on a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by the creature’s Wisdom (Perception) check.
	In addition, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to control the hand.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 98</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Roguish Archetype: Assassin</name><text>You focus your training on the grim art of death. Those who adhere to this archetype are diverse: hired killers, spies, bounty hunters, and even specially anointed priests trained to exterminate the enemies of their deity. Stealth, poison, and disguise help you eliminate your foes with deadly efficiency.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Assassin)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the disguise kit and the poisoner’s kit.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Assassinate (Assassin)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you are at your deadliest when you get the drop on your enemies. You have advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn’t taken a turn in the combat yet. In addition, any hit you score against a creature that is surprised is a critical hit.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Roguish Archetype: Inquisitive</name><text>As an archetypal Inquisitive, you excel at rooting out secrets and unraveling mysteries. You rely on your sharp eye for detail, but also on your finely honed ability to read the words and deeds of other creatures to determine their true intent. You excel at defeating creatures that hide among and prey upon ordinary folk, and your mastery of lore and your keen deductions make you well equipped to expose and end hidden evils.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 45</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Ear for Deceit (Inquisitive)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you develop a talent for picking out lies. Whenever you make a Wisdom (Insight) check to sense if a creature is lying, treat a roll of 7 or lower on the d20 as an 8.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 45</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Eye for Detail (Inquisitive)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use a bonus action to make a Wisdom (Perception) check to spot a hidden creature or object or to make an Intelligence (Investigation) check to uncover and decipher clues.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Insightful Fighting (Inquisitive)</name><text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to decipher an opponent’s tactics and develop a counter to them. As a bonus action, you can make a Wisdom (Insight) check against a creature you can see that isn’t incapacitated, contested by the target’s Charisma (Deception) check. If you succeed, you can use your Sneak Attack against that creature even if you don’t have advantage on the attack roll, but not if you have disadvantage on it.
	This benefit lasts for 1 minute or until you successfully use this feature against a different target.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Roguish Archetype: Mastermind</name><text>Your focus is on people and on the influence and secrets they have. Many spies, courtiers, and schemers follow this archetype, leading lives of intrigue. Words are your weapons as often as knives or poison, and secrets and favors are some of your favorite treasures.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master of Intrigue (Mastermind)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the disguise kit, the forgery kit, and one gaming set of your choice. You also learn two languages of your choice. 
	Additionally, you can unerringly mimic the speech patterns and accent of a creature that you hear speak for at least 1 minute, allowing you to pass yourself off as a native speaker of a particular land, provided that you know the language.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master of Tactics (Mastermind)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the Help action as a bonus action. Additionally, when you use the Help action to aid an ally in attacking a creature, the target of that attack can be within 30 feet of you, rather than 5 feet of you, if the target can see or hear you.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Roguish Archetype: Scout</name><text>You are skilled in stealth and surviving far from the streets of a city, allowing you to scout ahead of your companions during expeditions. Rogues who embrace this archetype are at home in the wilderness and among barbarians and rangers, and many Scouts serve as the eyes and ears of war bands. Ambusher, spy, bounty hunter—these are just a few of the roles that Scouts assume as they range the world.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Skirmisher (Scout)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you are difficult to pin down during a fight. You can move up to half your speed as a reaction when an enemy ends its turn within 5 feet of you. This movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Survivalist (Scout)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Nature and Survival skills if you don’t already have it. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those proficiencies.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional><mod><category>4</category><type>10</type></mod><mod><category>4</category><type>17</type></mod><proficiency>117</proficiency><proficiency>110</proficiency></feat><feat><name>Roguish Archetype: Swashbuckler</name><text>You focus your training on the art of the blade, relying on speed, elegance, and charisma in equal parts. While other warriors are brutes clad in heavy armor, your method of fighting looks more like performance. Duelists and pirates typically belong to this archetype.
	A Swashbuckler excels in single combat, and can fight with two weapons while safely darting away from an opponent.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fancy Footwork (Swashbuckler)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn how to land a strike and then slip away without reprisal. During your turn, if you make a melee attack against a creature, that creature cannot make opportunity attacks against you for the rest of your turn.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Rakish Audacity (Swashbuckler)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, your unmistakable confidence propels you into battle. You can give yourself a bonus to your initiative rolls equal to your Charisma modifier.
	You also gain an additional way to use your Sneak Attack: you don’t need advantage on the attack roll to use your Sneak Attack against a creature if you are within 5 feet of it, no other creatures are within 5 feet of you, and you don’t have disadvantage on the attack roll. All the other rules for Sneak Attack still apply to you
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 136
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Roguish Archetype: Thief</name><text>You hone your skills in the larcenous arts. Burglars, bandits, cutpurses, and other criminals typically follow this archetype, but so do rogues who prefer to think of themselves as professional treasure seekers, explorers, delvers, and investigators. In addition to improving your agility and stealth, you learn skills useful for delving into ancient ruins, reading unfamiliar languages, and using magic items you normally couldn’t employ.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Fast Hands (Thief)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, use your thieves’ tools to disarm a trap or open a lock, or take the Use an Object action.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Second-Story Work (Thief)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the ability to climb faster than normal; climbing no longer costs you extra movement.
	In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>4</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>5</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Uncanny Dodge</name><text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>6</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots></autolevel><autolevel><level>7</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Evasion</name><text>Beginning at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>8</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (2nd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>9</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Magical Ambush (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>Starting at 9th level, if you are hidden from a creature when you cast a spell on it, the creature has disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against the spell this turn.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 98</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Infiltration Expertise (Assassin)</name><text>Starting at 9th level, you can unfailingly create false identities for yourself. You must spend seven days and 25 gp to establish the history, profession, and affiliations for an identity. You can’t establish an identity that belongs to someone else. For example, you might acquire appropriate clothing, letters of introduction, and official-looking certification to establish yourself as a member of a trading house from a remote city so you can insinuate yourself into the company of other wealthy merchants.
	Thereafter, if you adopt the new identity as a disguise, other creatures believe you to be that person until given an obvious reason not to.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Steady Eye (Inquisitive)</name><text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) or Intelligence (Investigation) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Insightful Manipulator (Mastermind)</name><text>Starting at 9th level, if you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can learn certain information about its capabilities compared to your own. The DM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regard to two of the following characteristics of your choice: 
	 
• Intelligence score 
• Wisdom score 
• Charisma score 
• Class levels (if any) 
	 
	At the DM’s option, you might also realize you know a piece of the creature’s history or one of its personality traits, if it has any.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Superior Mobility (Scout)</name><text>At 9th level, your walking speed increases by 10 feet. If you have a climbing or swimming speed, this increase applies to that speed as well.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional><mod><type>13</type><value>10</value></mod></feat><feat><name>Panache (Swashbuckler)</name><text>At 9th level, your charm becomes extraordinarily beguiling. As an action, you can make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by a creature’s Wisdom (Insight) check. The creature must be able to hear you, and the two of you must share a language.
	If you succeed on the check and the creature is hostile to you, it has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you and can’t make opportunity attacks against targets other than you. This effect lasts for 1 minute, until one of your companions attacks the target or affects it with a spell, or until you and the target are more than 60 feet apart.
	If you succeed on the check and the creature isn’t hostile to you, it is charmed by you for 1 minute. While charmed, it regards you as a friendly acquaintance. This effect ends immediately if you or your companions do anything harmful to it.
	 
Charmed:
• A charmed creature can&#39;t attack the charmer or target the charmer with harmful abilities or magical effects.
	
• The charmer has advantage on any ability check to interact socially with the creature.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 136
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Supreme Sneak (Thief)</name><text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on a Dexterity (Stealth) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>10</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (3rd)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>11</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Reliable Talent</name><text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>12</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (4th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>13</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Versatile Trickster (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to distract targets with your mage hand. As a bonus action on your turn, you can designate a creature within 5 feet of the spectral hand created by the spell. Doing so gives you advantage on attack rolls against that creature until the end of the turn.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 98</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Imposter (Assassin)</name><text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to unerringly mimic another person’s speech, writing, and behavior. You must spend at least three hours studying these three components of the person’s behavior, listening to speech, examining handwriting, and observing mannerisms.
	Your ruse is indiscernible to the casual observer. If a wary creature suspects something is amiss, you have advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make to avoid detection.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Unerring Eye (Inquisitive)</name><text>Beginning at 13th level, your senses are almost impossible to foil. As an action, you sense the presence of illusions, shapechangers not in their original form, and other magic designed to deceive the senses within 30 feet of you, provided you aren’t blinded or deafened. You sense that an effect is attempting to trick you, but you gain no insight into what is hidden or into its true nature.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Misdirection (Mastermind)</name><text>Beginning at 13th level, you can sometimes cause another creature to suffer an attack meant for you. When you are targeted by an attack while a creature within 5 feet of you is granting you cover against that attack, you can use your reaction to have the attack target that creature instead of you.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Ambush Master (Scout)</name><text>Starting at 13th level, you excel at leading ambushes and acting first in a fight.
	You have advantage on initiative rolls. In addition, the first creature you hit during the first round of combat becomes easier for you and others to strike; attack rolls against that target have advantage until the start of your next turn.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Elegant Maneuver (Swashbuckler)</name><text>Starting at 13th level, you can use a bonus action on your turn to gain advantage on the next Dexterity (Acrobatics) or Strength (Athletics) check you make during the same turn.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 136
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Use Magic Device (Thief)</name><text>By 13th level, you have learned enough about the workings of magic that you can improvise the use of items even when they are not intended for you. You ignore all class, race, and level requirements on the use of magic items.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>14</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Blindsense</name><text>Starting at 14th level, if you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>15</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Slippery Mind</name><text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text><proficiency>4</proficiency></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>16</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (5th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>17</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Spell Thief (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to magically steal the knowledge of how to cast a spell from another spellcaster.
	Immediately after a creature casts a spell that targets you or includes you in its area of effect, you can use your reaction to force the creature to make a saving throw with its spellcasting ability modifier. The DC equals your spell save DC. On a failed save, you negate the spell’s effect against you, and you steal the knowledge of the spell if it is at least 1st level and of a level you can cast (it doesn’t need to be a wizard spell). For the next 8 hours, you know the spell and can cast it using your spell slots. The creature can’t cast that spell until the 8 hours have passed.
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 98</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Death Strike (Assassin)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, you become a master of instant death. When you attack and hit a creature that is surprised, it must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your Dexterity modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, double the damage of your attack against the creature.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Eye for Weakness (Inquisitive)</name><text>At 17th level, you learn to exploit a creature’s weaknesses by carefully studying its tactics and movement. While your Insightful Fighting feature applies to a creature, your Sneak Attack damage against that creature increases by 3d6.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Soul of Deceit (Mastermind)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, your thoughts can’t be read by telepathy or other means, unless you allow it. You can present false thoughts by making a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the mind reader’s Wisdom (Insight) check.
	Additionally, no matter what you say, magic that would determine if you are telling the truth indicates you are being truthful, if you so choose, and you can’t be compelled to tell the truth by magic.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 135
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 46</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Sudden Strike (Scout)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, you can strike with deadly speed. If you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack as a bonus action. This attack can benefit from your Sneak Attack even if you have already used it this turn, but you can’t use your Sneak Attack against the same target more than once in a turn.
	
Source: Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Master Duelist (Swashbuckler)</name><text>Beginning at 17th level, your mastery of the blade lets you turn failure into success in combat. If you miss with an attack roll, you can roll it again with advantage. Once you do so, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.
	
Source: Sword Coast Adventurer&#39;s Guide, p. 136
		Xanathar&#39;s Guide to Everything, p. 47</text><optional>1</optional></feat><feat><name>Thief&#39;s Reflexes (Thief)</name><text>When you reach 17th level, you have become adept at laying ambushes and quickly escaping danger. You can take two turns during the first round of any combat. You take your first turn at your normal initiative and your second turn at your initiative minus 10. You can’t use this feature when you are surprised.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text><optional>1</optional></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>18</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Elusive</name><text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren’t incapacitated.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>19</level><scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Ability Score Improvement (6th)</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM uses the optional Feats, you can instead take a feat.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 96</text></feat></autolevel><autolevel><level>20</level><spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional><slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><feat><name>Stroke of Luck</name><text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.
	Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
	
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 97</text></feat></autolevel><spellAbility>3</spellAbility></class><background><id>1169</id><name>Enfant Des Rues</name><align>Chaotique Neutre</align><personality>Je pense que tous ceux qui sont gentils avec moi ont en réalité une mauvaise intention.</personality><ideals>Les faibles doivent s&#39;élever, et les élites et les puissants doivent être mis à terre. Le changement est dans la nature des choses.</ideals><bonds>J&#39;ai échappé à mon sort en volant une personne très importante, et je suis recherché pour cela.</bonds><flaws>Ce n&#39;est pas du vol si j&#39;en ai plus besoin que quelqu&#39;un d&#39;autre.</flaws><feat><name>Histoire</name><text>Haey s&#39;est retrouvé dans l&#39;exécution d&#39;un cambriolage très risqué ayant pour cible un proche de l&#39;un des grands ducs qui dirigent la cité de La porte de Baldur. Il est le seul a s&#39;être sorti vivant de l&#39;opération mais il est maintenant traqué par les membre de la Guilde missionné par le Grand Ducs, Ulder Ravengard. Il décide alors de voyager vers le Nord jusqu&#39;à Luskan, un endroit malfamé ou le crime paie bien.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><feat><name>Capacité : Secrets de la ville</name><text>Vous connaissez les ruelles secrètes et vous vous déplacez à toute vitesse dans les cités. Vous pouvez trouver des passages dans un labyrinthe urbain, passages que d&#39;autres rateraient. Lorsque vous n&#39;êtes pas dans une situation de combat, vous (et les compagnons que vous menez) pouvez vous déplacer en ville d&#39;un point à un autre deux fois plus rapidement que ce que votre vitesse vous permettrait en temps normal.
 
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 141</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat><proficiency>116</proficiency><proficiency>115</proficiency></background>
<xp>4310</xp><unarmed>1</unarmed><slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent><item><name>Leather Armor</name><text>The breastplate and shoulder protectors of this armor are made of leather that has been stiffened by being boiled in oil. The rest of the armor is made of softer and more flexible materials.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 144</text><type>1</type><slot>5</slot><value>10.0</value><weight>10.0</weight><ac>11</ac></item><item><name>Shortsword</name><text>Proficiency: martial, shortsword
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 149</text><type>5</type><slot>2</slot><value>10.0</value><weight>2.0</weight><damage1H>1d6</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>1034</weaponProperty><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><item><name>Dagger</name><text>Proficiency: simple, dagger
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 149</text><type>5</type><slot>4</slot><value>2.0</value><weight>1.0</weight><damage1H>1d4</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty><weaponRange>20</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><item><name>Shortbow</name><text>Proficiency: simple, shortbow
Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 149</text><type>6</type><value>25.0</value><weight>2.0</weight><damage1H>1d6</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>257</weaponProperty><weaponRange>80</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>320</weaponLongRange><mod><type>1</type></mod></item><item><name>Arrows</name><text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 150</text><type>7</type><quantity>10</quantity><value>0.05</value><weight>0.05</weight></item><item><name>Traveler&#39;s Clothes</name><text>Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 150</text><slot>1</slot><value>2.0</value><weight>4.0</weight></item><container><label>Burglar&#39;s Pack</label><name>Backpack</name><value>16.0</value><weight>5.0</weight><carried>1</carried><item><name>Ball bearings (bag of 1,000)</name><weight>2.0</weight></item><item><name>Lames de Bonnes facture</name><text>Lames achetées en prévision de la fabrication de lames d’assassins accrochées aux poignets.</text><quantity>2</quantity><weight>2.0</weight></item><item><name>Potion of Healing</name><detail>common</detail><text>You regain 2d4+2 hit points when you drink this potion.  The potion&#39;s red liquid glimmers when agitated.

Source: Dungeon Master&#39;s Guide p. 187</text><type>12</type><quantity>0</quantity><weight>0.5</weight><magic>1</magic><roll>2d4+2</roll></item><item><name>Gâteau Au Monstre</name><detail>rare</detail><text>Un biscuit sec violet vif, très compact mais se délite comme de la cendre une fois en bouche, n’a aucun gout. Une fois avalé, il permet de se déplacer dans le plan de l’ombre pendant 30 secondes avant revenir automatiquement au plan materiel.</text><type>14</type><value>100.0</value><magic>1</magic></item><item><name>String (10 feet)</name></item><item><name>Bell</name></item><item><name>Candle</name><quantity>5</quantity></item><item><name>Crowbar</name><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Hammer</name><weight>3.0</weight></item><item><name>Piton</name><quantity>10</quantity><weight>0.25</weight></item><item><name>Lantern, hooded</name><weight>2.0</weight></item><item><name>Oil (flask)</name><quantity>2</quantity><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Rations (1 day)</name><quantity>5</quantity><weight>2.0</weight></item><item><name>Tinderbox</name><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Waterskin</name><weight>5.0</weight></item><item><name>Rope, hempen (50 feet)</name><weight>10.0</weight></item><item><name>Thieves&#39; Tools</name><text>This set of tools includes a small file, a set of lock picks, a small mirror mounted on a metal handle, a set of narrow-bladed scissors, and a pair of pliers. Proficiency with these tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make to disarm traps or open locks.
	Perhaps the most common tools used by adventurers, thieves’ tools are designed for picking locks and foiling traps. Proficiency with the tools also grants you a general knowledge of traps and locks.
	Components: Thieves’ tools include a small file, a set of lock picks, a small mirror mounted on a metal handle, a set of narrow-bladed scissors, and a pair of pliers.
	History: Your knowledge of traps grants you insight when answering questions about locations that are renowned for their traps.
	Investigation and Perception: You gain additional insight when looking for traps, because you have learned a variety of common signs that betray their presence.
	Set a Trap: Just as you can disable traps, you can also set them. As part of a short rest, you can create a trap using items you have on hand. The total of your check becomes the DC for someone else’s attempt to discover or disable the trap. The trap deals damage appropriate to the materials used in crafting it (such as poison or a weapon) or damage equal to half the total of your check, whichever the DM deems appropriate.
	

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 154</text><value>25.0</value><weight>1.0</weight></item><item><name>Carte de Ville: Portes de Baldur</name></item><item><name>Statuette de Grenouille en Jade</name><value>50.0</value><weight>2.0</weight></item></container><container><name>Bourse</name><ignore>1</ignore><carried>1</carried><item><name>Gold (gp)</name><type>15</type><quantity>219</quantity><value>1.0</value><weight>0.02</weight></item><item><name>Silver (sp)</name><text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).
	With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.
	One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.
	One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.
	In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.
	A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 143</text><type>15</type><slot>1</slot><quantity>59</quantity><weight>0.02</weight></item><item><name>Copper (cp)</name><text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).
	With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don&#39;t usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.
	One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer&#39;s work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night&#39;s rest in a poor inn.
	One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.
	In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.
	A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player&#39;s Handbook p. 143</text><type>15</type><quantity>15</quantity><weight>0.02</weight></item></container><monster><label>Diablo</label><name>Rat</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><hd>1d8</hd><speed>20 ft.</speed><senses>darkvision 30 ft.</senses><cr>-3</cr><environment>1152</environment><trait><name>Source</name><text>Monster Manual, p. 335
Player&#39;s Handbook, p. 309</text></trait><trait><name>Keen Smell</name><text>The rat has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text></trait><action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +0 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 piercing damage.</text><attack><name>Bite</name><damage>1</damage></attack></action><abilities>2,11,9,2,10,4,</abilities><hpMax>1</hpMax><hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent></monster><abilities>12,17,12,9,12,11,</abilities><hpMax>32</hpMax><hpCurrent>24</hpCurrent></character></pc>